pitneyworks.com 2018-11-20

# Privacy Statement | Pitney Bowes

This Privacy Statement is effective as of 27 February 2018.  
Pitney Bowes is committed to respecting the privacy of our clients and users. This Privacy Statement describes how our websites, services and products operate, and how we collect, use, and share information. This Privacy Statement applies to pb.com and Pitney Bowes websites, services and products that collect data and display these terms, and that are owned and operated by Pitney Bowes and Pitney Bowes subsidiaries, collectively, "Pitney Bowes".  Pitney Bowes websites, services and products are referred to in this statement as "Sites".  These terms do not apply to Pitney Bowes sites that do not display or link to this statement or that have their own privacy statements.

The following topics are presented in this Privacy Statement:

  1. Collecting Personal Information from Site Users
  2. Collecting Other Information
  3. Using and Retaining Personal Information
  4. Sharing Personal Information
  5. Protecting Personal Information
  6. Cross Border Data Transfer
  7. Visiting Non-Pitney Bowes Websites
  8. EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Compliance
  9. Country-Specific Requirements
  10. Your Choices
  11. Your Rights to Access Personal Information
  12. Changes to this Privacy Statement
  13. Contact Us

**1\. Collecting Personal Information from Site Users**

In order to provide you with access to certain services or data within our Sites, we may require that you provide certain Personal Information (information that identifies an individual either alone or in combination with other data). Pitney Bowes also collects non-personal information that does not, on its own, identify an individual person. When non-personal information is combined with other information so that it does identify an individual person, we treat that combination as Personal Information.

The following are examples of the types of Personal Information that may be collected directly from you (or someone acting on your behalf):

  * Contact information (including Name, Street Address, Email Address, Telephone Number)
  * Government issued IDs (such as tax identification number)
  * Username, password, and other information used in combination to verify identity
  * Financial information (including credit/debit card and bank account information, credit and repayment history, and payment default information)
  * Geolocation, demographic, shipping/receiving, billing, and other information related to the purchase or delivery of Pitney Bowes products and services or services you access through the Sites
  * Any other Personal Information or characteristics about an individual that is connected to one of the above, such as date or place of birth, geographical indicators, or photographic images

By accessing and utilizing our Sites, you consent to the collection, use, disclosure, storage and processing of Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.  Please note, by law you are not required to provide us with your Personal Information. By electing to not share your Personal Information with us, you may be unable to take advantage of our Sites and we may be unable to provide you with all of the functionality we offer through our Sites.

**2\. Collecting Other Information**

Pitney Bowes Sites use several automatic data collection tools and techniques including cookies, clickstream, and web beacons.

**Cookies**  
Some of our Sites use "cookies" which are a small amount of data (often including a unique identifier), which is sent to your browser from a website and stored on your computer’s hard drive.   We may use cookies so that we can better serve visitors on our Sites, understand usage and improve the content and offerings on our Sites. Cookies may be placed by us or by our third party service providers.

We, or our service providers, may: (1) use cookies to collect aggregate information about website users on an anonymous basis or (2) share aggregate demographic and usage information with our prospective and actual business partners, advertisers, and other third parties for any business purpose.

If you prefer not to have cookies, most web browsers include an option that allows you to not accept them. However, without cookies you may be unable to take full advantage of all of our Site features and some portions of our Sites may not function properly.

**Clickstream**  
We may collect information about the "clickstream" of our customers during their visit to our Sites. This clickstream data contains the pages the visitors came from, the navigational paths they took, and the areas of the Site they visited.  From time to time we track such information inside and outside of our Sites. Additionally, we may track and match clickstream data with Personal Information you provide to us in order to deliver content and other offerings - i.e., products and services that might improve your customer experience.  We may also share clickstream data with third parties in an aggregate or otherwise anonymous format. 

**Web Beacon**  
Certain email communications you receive from us may contain "web beacons." Web beacons consist of a line of code on our Sites that delivers a small graphic image. The web beacon may not be visible as it is a 1x1 pixel that is often designed to blend into the background of a web page. Web beacons allow us to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the web beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the web beacon appears, the time the page containing the web beacon was viewed, the browser type used to view the page and the information in cookies. We use web beacons for activities such as monitoring the effectiveness of the headlines in our emails or the ad banners.

**IP Address**  
Your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address is a numerical label assigned to each device (e.g., computer, printer, mobile device, or server) and is usually associated with the place from which you enter the internet.  It is how devices find each other on a network.  We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers, gather broad demographic information, gather geographic data, and administer our Sites.

**Tracking Requests**  
We do not act on, alter, or change our Site behavior upon receiving Do Not Track requests from your browser.

**3.  Using and Retaining Personal Information**

Personal Information we collect through our Sites may be used to provide information regarding our products and services, or for marketing and promotions we believe you may find of interest.  We also may use the Personal Information you provide for our internal purposes, such as Site customisation, enhancement or development, administration and operation of our Sites, data analytics, and compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures, including performance of Pitney Bowes obligations under sales contracts, leases or licenses between you and Pitney Bowes.

We retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement, unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law; or to otherwise fulfill a legal obligation.

**4\. Sharing Personal Information**

Pitney Bowes may rent, sell or otherwise share your Personal Information where permitted by law, for example:

  1. within the Pitney Bowes family of businesses,
  2. with third parties that perform services for us or on our behalf (such as credit card companies, credit and/or investigative reporting agencies, finance companies, transport companies, consultants, advisors and market research firms), or
  3. for marketing campaigns conducted by us or other companies or organisations that offer products or services we believe may be of interest to our clients.

Our service providers are required to keep confidential and secure the Personal Information received from us in accordance with this Privacy Statement and they may not use it for any other purpose other than for the purpose for which Pitney Bowes provided it to the service provider.

We may also make information available to third parties in the following circumstances:

  1. When we have a good faith belief it is required by law or to otherwise cooperate with law enforcement activity;
  2. When we have a good faith belief it is necessary to protect our rights or property from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful activity; or
  3. In the event of a proposed merger, acquisition, liquidation, dissolution or sale of assets.

In these circumstances, your consent will not be required, but we will attempt to notify you, to the extent the law requires.

Depending upon local law, you may either opt in or opt out of having your Personal Information shared and/or for marketing purposes.  In the event you opt-in, we will use and share your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Statement.  In the event you opt-out, we will share your preference with the applicable third parties as appropriate.  For information on how to do this, see the Your Choices section of this Privacy Statement below.

**5\. Protecting Personal Information**

We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect the Personal Information we collect and process.

**6\. Cross Border Data Transfer**

Pitney Bowes Inc. and its wholly-owned U.S. subsidiaries that receive Personal Information from countries outside of the United States adhere to applicable law and regulations regarding client, partner and employee Personal Information moving across geographical and jurisdictional borders.  This includes the use of data transfer agreements and model contractual clauses, where available, between our corporate entities, our partners and our clients where required. 

Additional information may be found under the Country-Specific Requirements section for the geographies you are located in.

**7\. Visiting Non-Pitney Bowes Websites**

Our Sites may contain links to other websites that operate independently from Pitney Bowes. Linked websites may have their own privacy statements or notices.  If you visit any linked websites we strongly suggest you review their privacy statement.  Any information you provide when you visit a nonaffiliated Pitney Bowes website is subject to the privacy statements posted on those websites.  We are not responsible for the content of any websites that are not affiliated with or owned by Pitney Bowes, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of those websites.     

**8\. EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Compliance**

Pitney Bowes participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, processing and retention of Personal Information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. 

We have certified to the Department of Commerce that we adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Statement and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome)

Pitney Bowes is responsible for the processing of Personal Information it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  Pitney Bowes complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of Personal Information from the EU or Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to Personal Information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Pitney Bowes is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the United States Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, we may be required to disclose Personal Information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In compliance with the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles, Pitney Bowes commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Information.  If you believe Pitney Bowes processes your Personal Information within the scope of our Privacy Shield certification, you may direct any inquiries or complaints concerning our compliance to us at the following information in the Contact Us section below.

Pitney Bowes will respond within 45 days.  If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact JAMS, our U.S-based third party dispute resolution provider, free of charge at <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield>.

If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, you may be able to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. Please contact or visit the Privacy Shield website at <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint> for more information or to file a complaint.  The services of the Privacy Shield website are provided at no cost to you.   

**9\. Country-Specific Requirements**

Pitney Bowes Inc. is a global corporation with subsidiary companies located around the world. This Privacy Statement establishes our global principles (to the extent the law permits and/or requires) for the collection, use and disclosure of information gathered through our Sites. The country in which you are doing business with us or where the Site you are visiting is located or hosted may have specific requirements concerning Personal Information and may be found below.

**10\. Your Choices**

If you are a Pitney Bowes customer, you will continue to receive transactional communications about your account and the Pitney Bowes products and services which you own, lease, rent, license or to which you subscribe.  In some jurisdictions, you may have to opt-in to receive any additional marketing communications from us.  If you wish to opt out of receiving marketing communications from Pitney Bowes, you may do so by (i) following the instructions provided in our marketing communications, or (ii) indicating your preferences on the relevant account profile/preferences section (such as Your Account), or (iii) referring to the instructions provided in the Contact Us section below. 

Some of our products and services contain settings that allow users or administrators to control how the products collect information.  If you wish to request changes to your Personal Information, you may do so by (i) indicating your preferences on the relevant account profile/preferences section (such as Your Account), or (iii) referring to the instructions provided in the Contact Us section below.  Please note, by electing to not share certain Personal Information with us, we may be unable to provide you with all of the functionality we offer through our Sites. 

Where required by law you may request access to your Personal Information that we maintain.  As permitted by law we may charge a reasonable fee for providing access to Personal Information but we do not charge for lodging a request for access.

**11\. Your Rights to Access Personal Information**

Where required by law, you may request access and/or make corrections to your Personal Information that we maintain. When accessing or updating your Personal Information, we may ask you to verify your identity before we can act on your request.  Please note that we may reject requests, or limit the information we provide access to, if we determine it could risk the privacy of others or if unreasonable or repetitive, or if it would require disproportionate effort.  As permitted by law, we may charge a reasonable fee for providing access to Personal Information, but we do not charge for lodging a request for access.  If you would like to make a request please follow the instructions in the **Contact Us** section below.

**12\. Changes to this Privacy Statement**

Pitney Bowes may change this Privacy Statement from time to time at its discretion. We will indicate at the top of the Privacy Statement when it was most recently updated. We will not use your Personal Information in ways that differ materially from this Privacy Statement without prior notice to you, and in no event will we use your Personal Information in ways prohibited by law. Your continued use of our Sites indicates your consent to this Privacy Statement and any amended version of it.

**13\. Contact Us**

To opt out of marketing communications, [click here to Unsubscribe](https://web.pitneybowes.com/unsub-secure) and you will be removed from Pitney Bowes promotional/marketing email lists. Please note, if you are a Pitney Bowes customer, you will continue to receive transactional communications about your account and the Pitney Bowes products and services which you own, lease, rent, and license or to which you subscribe.

If you would like to make changes to your Personal Information (such as address information and phone number) **_click here_**.

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at:

Global Data Protection Office

c/o Pitney Bowes Inc.

3001 Summer St

Stamford, CT USA 06926-0700

or

Email us @ [privacyoffice@pb.com](mailto:privacyoffice@pb.com)

Please see below for contact information for the following countries, which should be used if you have a question, comment or compliant about this Privacy Statement for your specific country:
